If you've been considering relocating to
the central Texas area and Temple has
caught your eye, you may be wondering
what our shopping and retail scene look
like here. Well, today I'll be giving
you a tour of our top shopping centers.
And honestly, this is really just a
great video if you want to see the area
a little bit. Hi, and welcome back to
Living in Central Texas. I'm Andrea
Dudik, your local broker and guide to
all things real estate here in the
Central Texas area. If you're new to the
channel, don't forget to like,
subscribe, and click the bell
notification so that you can stay up to
date on all things real estate here in
Central Texas.
Okay, we're going to start out on South
31st Street headed north headed towards
the loop as well as the hospitals.
South 31st is really cool. You have a
bunch of established real estate
communities and you have a lot of new
construction as well at the end of 31st
at FM93.
Now, while this side of town is a little
bit older, it looks like they're
updating a lot of it. And this is one of
three
plazas or areas that we're going to be
taking a look at today. It's currently,
what's today's date? Hope October 3rd.
third and it's 80° and sunny and
beautiful. Okay, so where we currently
are on 31st Street, you're probably a
whopping 3 minutes away from Baylor
Scott and White, the main hospital.
Same thing about 3 minutes away from
MLAN Children's Hospital.
You have everything you could need on
this side of town. You have liquor
stores. Um, you have Academy Sporting
Goods down Marlin Wood. And then in
this shopping center
right here, we have Chick-fil-A. Of
course, Texas loves their Chick-fil-A. I
love their Chick-fil-A. You have uh
Sam's Club and Walmart. We don't have a
Costco here. I think the nearest one is
in Colleen.
Rock.
>> Round Rock. Nearest ones in Round Rock.
Today is Friday, midm morning,
just if you want to get a feel of
traffic right now.
So, this is our Sam's Club.
As you can see, Friday afternoon, not
super busy. Quite honestly, I don't I
mean, being from Vegas, I don't really
think Temple gets busy in general. Um,
when people talk about traffic, they're
like, "Well, should I leave early?" And
like, you might want to leave an extra 5
minutes maybe. But unless there's some
crazy accident, I don't really think you
hit traffic here on 31st Street.
you know, around, I don't know, four or
five o'clock, you might hit some traffic
and add an extra five minutes, but grand
scheme of things. This is our Walmart,
one of our Walmarts. So, we have four
Walmarts in the Well, we have two in
Temple, three in Temple, and then one in
Belton. Today, we're really just going
to be focusing on Temple. We are not
going to be hitting uh downtown Temple
Belin at all. I think those are areas
that are worthy of their own separate
videos. Now, what we're going to take a
look at right off of 31st Street is our
mall.
I use that term loosely. We do have a
mall. It's kind of funny. Um I don't my
husband so he's from here. His parents,
my in-laws, actually had a little cookie
store here in the mall once upon a time.
I think that's so cute. But there's
really not a lot to this mall. There are
some stores. I frequently go here for
Dillards. We had a J C Penney, but it
shut down. I think if you're looking for
a real mall, you're probably going to
head to Colleen or Round Rock for Round
Rock Premium Outlets. But Colleen has a
really great mall. And what I really
love about this area is even if you
can't find exactly what you're looking
for for this area, you're so close to
Colleen and Harker Heights. So, I don't
know, 25 minutes, 30 minutes away from,
you know, the Colleen Mall. Um, another
30 minutes away from Round Rock Premium
Outlets. I go there a lot for what is
that? Black Friday shopping. I love
going to the outlets. But this is our
mall. So that's the Dillards. Nothing's
really open right now. It's still a
little bit early, but they have other
things connected to the mall.
This is
Extreme Jump. Um, we have kids and we do
a lot of birthday parties there. I think
super reasonable but really fun. They
have laser tag, a bunch of games,
trampolines.
Uh, my youngest broke her leg there.
Yeah, that's where J C Penney used to
be. But
they also have a movie theater attached
to this mall
floor and decor.
We have a lot of car washes. A lot of so
many. It's kind of a running joke here,
especially off of West Adams. They just
keep putting up car washes. Apparently,
that's the business to be in. I'm not
going to be focusing so much on food
today. I can do another video at some
point.
There's also an Aldi's
if you like Aldi's.
And then right off of the loop connected
to 31st Street, um
we have HB, which HB is our local to
Texas grocery store. Absolutely love
them. Even their generic brands are
amazing. Super reasonably priced. I'm a
little biased, but I would say most
people prefer HB over Walmart any day.
We have HB in this shopping plaza,
Dollar Tree, Beiel's. There's Kohl's
with a Sephora inside, Jason's Deli,
shoe department, some small little
places like European Wax Center, but
I'll give you a quick little tour of
inside this HB. There's also a Planet
Fitness. I'd love to get maybe when we
go up that way, we can get a view of the
Temple Mall sign.
>> Yeah. So, the Temple Mall has a lot of
smaller stores in it, too. There's a
cafe, a Cotton Patch Cafe, Kasa Olay,
some boutiques, Perfume Mania. There's
really not a lot of big chain
stores in there. They're trying to
revive it. I would not say Temple is
known for its Temple Mall, but we're
known for a lot of other really great
things.
I will say
grocery stores get busy Sunday after
church.
That to me is the busiest time.
Everyone's doing their Sunday routine,
church shopping. There's also a
Starbucks over here next to HB. Call
this Starbucks on 31st Street. There's
also Starbucks on Adams. If you're a
coffee junkie like me,
you know exactly where those places are,
or at least you want to if you're moving
here.
If you move to Temple
and you go into the grocery store, you
need to add at least 10 minutes for
visiting with strangers
because everyone wants to get to know
you and they genuinely mean it and it's
the sweetest thing. It was definitely a
culture shock and adjustment when I
moved here because I'd be standing in
line and people would compliment
something or ask where I was from or and
then you would just start visiting and
it's a really really sweet town for
that. You can see out here we have our
Starbucks and our water burger.
Kohl's on the other side. Okay. Okay.
So, so like I said from right here you
can see the hospital the Baylor Scott
and White from
the exit of HB. So in terms of proximity
if you were looking to live over here to
be close to the hospital really
everything you need is right here.
Across from the hospital there is a
little strip mall of a ton of
restaurants.
I recently did a video living near
Baylor Scott and White that really maps
out this area including food and some
neighborhood pockets and home prices
from the MLS.
Okay, so we're about to hop on the loop.
You can see the hospital here and we're
going to go check out a newer shopping
plaza. These are
three minutes away from each other.
So, we have all this shopping on 31st
Street.
Bunch of miscellaneous restaurants
along this frontage. Hotels, too.
>> Oh, tons of hotels.
Mexico.
Little Mexico. Great Mexican
restaurants.
Okay, we're going to head into this next
plaza. This one is,
I think, growing pretty quickly. One of
the more popular shopping plazas.
We have Hobby Lobby for all of your home
decor musthaves.
Pizza, wings, and things. They have this
local crearyy called Freezing Point. I
love it. If you're familiar with Cold
Stone, it's a similar style
where
you pick ice cream and they mix in all
the things. The girls love that.
You have Petco.
Bath and Body Works,
Five Below,
the World's Most Dangerous Store, Ulta.
>> And the second most
>> Yeah, second one.
HomeGoods. That was the first job I ever
had when I was 16 in Vegas was film.
Then we have
Marshalls Ross.
There's also a Chase Bank in this plaza.
Mall theisters, which is a deli that's
got sandwiches,
potatoes,
and then we're going to continue to head
up
the frontage road and the loop
probably another 3 minutes up the
street. As you can see, everything is
super super close here. You're never too
far away from anything. And even if you
wanted to go to Belton,
you're really never more than 10 to 15
minutes away from most areas.
Okay, we're at the intersection of I35
and HK Dodge and Loop.
Huge shopping plaza. I would say this is
Temple's main shopping plaza. On one
side, you have restaurants, Olive
Garden.
On this other side here, there's some
more. There's like IHOP,
Chili's, an AT&T store, some slates, but
this is the main one. This is our Target
shopping plaza. We have some restaurants
in here as well. We have BJ's Brew
House, Chipotle,
Mimi's Thai Cuisine. Mimi's is wonderful
if you like Thai food. Here we have Best
Buy,
Home Depot.
You also have Specs Wine and Spirits,
Sally's Beauty,
PetSmart,
Boot Barn, Western and Workware,
Michaels Arts and Crafts
and Target. The only time I've really
seen Target busy
is again Sundays after church and
holidays. That pretty pretty much sums
up this shopping center. Our next
main one or the last one we're going to
check out is West Adams. West Adams has
really developed even since I've been
here. I've been here about 10 years now.
So from this shopping plaza, you're
looking at about
7 minutes
from our next shopping on West Adams.
So we are uh about to get off of HK
Dodge and and circle loop on over to
West Adams. Car dealerships a lot along
these ways. We have uh Volkswagen
down off of 35. You have BMW.
Now, this little loop around onto West
Adams does get busy because West Adams
is basically our main thoroughfare
through Temple leading into Belton. And
it's just growing so quickly and there's
so many houses
um popping up that this does get a
little congested. But again, you might
add 5 to 10 minutes to your commute and
not an astronomical amount of time. In
this area, you're going to have
Wildflower Country Club, which is our
golf community.
That one's really cool because you're
about 5 to seven minutes away from the
hospital. You're right off of Adams to
all your shopping and
your 10 car washes.
But this area is newer and more recently
developed. Terms of working out, you
have Anytime Fitness here. There's T3.
We were It's back in near our shopping
plaza where Marshalls, Ross, and Hobby
Lobby were. There's a T3. That's a
really cool smaller gym. Uh there's
Fieldhouse, which
that's for
the the the hardcore people. I don't
even think they have AC in there. It's
like hot. Okay. So along Adams, you'll
find a ton of smaller
food amenities. We're going to hop over
here
and check out.
This is right here on West Adams is
where most of our shopping is. We have
Starbucks off we say Starbucks off West
Adams. Nail salon, Grab a Green, AT&T.
You have a little children's clinic.
This is a Walmart.
I usually get my gas right here. Do gas.
Starbucks.
There's not an HB right here. If you're
looking for
HB, you have to go to 31st
or hop on over to Belin.
On the other side of the street, you
have Crumble Cookies, Pilates, Smoky
Moe's Barbecue. Pat Creek is really fun.
It's a burger place. They have an
outdoor play area for kids.
If you're looking for clothing,
I would say probably Dillards, Target.
Um, we have a bunch of boutiques. Texas
is really big on their boutiques, so
we'll hop in and see Brickwood Boutique
off of West Adams.
There's also,
is it Whimsies
in Belton? There's a bunch of little
boutiques and stuff in downtown Temple.
So on the corner of Adams and Old Waco
Road, you have a premier ER.
I actually really like that place,
especially if you they have a clinic
side and a ER side. And so if you have
something going on, it's really not very
busy and you don't have to go to the
main hospital. This is a great little
segue in between. when I had my
gallbladder taken, when I had something
going on with my gall, I I went there
and they're like, "Oh, you have to have
your gallbladder taken out." But I was
only in there for an hour and had all of
these tests done and then I was able to
go to Austin. If you go there and
there's something emergent and they
decide, you know, it's big, then they
can transport you to the main ER. But I
have a lot of clients who like the
location of this just for comfort
of knowing there's something right here
and accessible if there's an emergency.
Okay, we're going to pop over here. So,
on this side of the street,
this is the south side of Adams.
We have
Salad and Go, Chipotle,
Summer Moon, Coffee,
Stretch Lab, Mod Pizza,
our last main shopping plaza off of West
Adams. They have Nail Spa Allure, which
is where I get my nails done. I love
Sammy. But cute little nail salon in
there. We just got a tropical smoothie
cafe.
Larib woodfire
Italian. They've got pizza, Italian
steak,
Brickwood Boutique. We're going to hop
in there and take a look so you can see
how cute it is.
Soul Garden,
which is Korean barbecue. It is awesome.
You have Three West, which is like it's
an ale house that has burgers and
grilled food.
Bronco Nutrition, Taz Indian Cuisine.
Bunch of cute little restaurants in
here.
And Brickwood Boutique. Let's go take a
look.
They have the cutest little boutique
clothes, knickknacks, gifts, some cute
shoes.
[Music]
Okay, that wraps up our tour of retail
and shopping here in Temple, Texas. I'd
love to know what you thought of this
video. Was it helpful? Would you like to
see more videos like this? Are you more
interested in home tours? Let me know in
the comments below. And thank you again
so much for watching. Until next time,
I'm Andrea Dudik, realtor and associate
broker here in the Central Texas area.
[Music]